Anna Chavez

IT Recruiter - Tech One IT

Avondale, AZ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Anna-Chavez/6abefec15cf82f51

Pro-active, enthusiastic and competitive team player with a diverse background in sales and post-secondary education. An advocate of servant leadership and customer service, with a strong record of achievement in building partnerships and community relations. Expert communicator, highly motivated and intuitive with effective human relations; known for "hunting" skills, cold calling, and getting to the decision maker.

- Strong documentation and writing
- Expertise in problem-solving and analysis
- Exhibits the ability to make sound decisions under demanding conditions
- A meticulous planner with tremendous work ethic and integrity
- Proficient in MS Office Suite and CRM data entry and management.
- Excellent verbal, written, and analytical communication.
- Ability to build customer relationships and provide exceptional follow through.
- Outgoing personality and great polished impression.
- · Outstanding organizational and multi-tasking abilities; time management.
- Strong presentation skills group or individual with ability to overcome objections.
- Strong problem solving, influencing, negotiating.
- High volume phone and web marketing skills converting to face to face sales calls.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Recruiter

Tech One IT - Tempe, AZ - 2016 to Present

- Work collaboratively with Account Managers and internal staff to match candidates with the right opportunity.
- Interview candidates to assess skills, experience, availability, compensation requirements and willingness to travel
- Preform reference and background checks to verify hiring information.
- Recruit, interview and place IT professionals in contract, contract-to-hire, and FTE positions with clients.
- Provide the highest quality and customer service to both clients and candidates.
- Provide consistent communication and career guidance to candidates.
- Participate in industry trade associations to increase Company presence within the local IT community.
- Perform in-person and phone interviews with candidates to obtain leads and market information.
- Make recommendations to Account Managers.
- Coordinate interviews with the hiring managers.
- Follow up on the interview process status.
- Maintaining relationships with both internal and external clients to ensure staffing goals are achieved.
- Communicate employer information and benefits during screening process.

Internet Sales Manager

Phoenix, AZ - 2015 to 2016

Automobile Sales

- Strong verbal and written communication via phone, email, text, face to face.
- Convert phone call and internet leads to appointments to sales (10 12% close ratio).
- Excellent organizational skills, follow up, and attention to detail.
- Respond to customer inquiries relating to vehicles, products, and services via the internet, phone, text.

- Present new and pre-owned vehicles to customers in an attractive and highly informative fashion that promoted a prompt sale.
- Consultative approach to identify prospect's needs/wants.
- Maintain an ongoing relationship with customers to encourage networking and repeat business.
- Meet sales goals on commission pay structure.

Business Development Manager

Arizona Title / Escrow Companies - Phoenix, AZ - 2010 to 2015

- Acquire new customers for an assigned territory with business to business networking, cold calling, social media and other means to develop pipeline of new business for Company.
- Entrepreneurial experience and goal-driven focus.
- Drive sales revenue and market share by managing a defined territory to achieve quota.
- Prospect new clients through cold and warm lead generation.
- Work with clients to understand and identify their strategic vision, objectives and needs while aligning Company's products and services where business opportunities exist.
- Develop strong relationships with clients and deliver high levels of client care.
- Proposals, presentations, product demonstrations.
- Strong client-facing skills and effective selling to an executive, owner, and/or decision maker with a consultative approach.
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills.
- Demonstrate fearless cold calling, prospecting and a business acumen including sales quota achievement and closing sales.
- Ability to successfully work autonomously while demonstrating excellent time management skills.
- Maintained client retention by enhancing relationships, presenting new products/services.
- Set up meetings between client decision maker and Company's Leaders/Principals.

Online Academic Advisor School of Education

Grand Canyon University - Phoenix, AZ - 2009 to 2010

- Guidance counselor providing educational resources and assistance to student and prospects for enrollment into Bachelor and Master degree programs.
- Plan schedules, recommend courses, determine appropriate education solutions/plan.
- Follow through and track advancement of students.
- Respond to complex inquiries relating to program requirements, curriculum and course offerings.
- Advise undergraduate and graduate students on the development of individual learning outcomes based on their skills, goals, responsibilities and experiences.

Residential Realtor, Arizona

- 2005 to 2009
- Provide guidance and assist sellers and buyers in marketing and purchasing property for the right price under the best terms.
- Inter-mediate negotiation processes, consult clients on market conditions, prices, mortgages, legal requirements and related matters, ensuring a fair and honest dealing.
- Perform comparative market analysis to estimate properties' value.
- Display and market real residential property to possible buyers.
- Determine clients' needs and financial abilities to propose solutions that suit them.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Business Management

University of Phoenix - Phoenix, AZ 2001

Religious Education Teacher

St. Thomas - Goodyear, AZ